Guide to the Edward Ginzton Papers SC0330
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Edward Ginzton papers
circa 1937-1992
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard)
SC0330
105 Linear Feet
Papers regarding Ginzton's activities at Stanford University, with Varian Associates, and on national committees and local organizations. Includes correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, journals, publications, technical reports, manufacturing reports, oral history materials, and photographs. Also includes correspondence, publications, biographical material and manuscripts of Russell, Sigurd and Dorothy Varian.
Information about Access
Partially restricted: for more information, contact the archivist.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Co-founder of Varian Associates and a pioneer in microwave tube technology and linear accelerator development. As a graduate student at Stanford during the 1930's, Ginzton joined Russell and Sigurd Varian and physics professors William W. Hansen and David L. Webster to develop the klystron tube, an integral part of radar and the linear accelerator concept. After working on radar systems during World War II, Ginzton returned to Stanford in 1946 as a professor of applied physics. He joined Hansen in the establishment of the Microwave Laboratory at Stanford. Becoming director of the Laboratory in 1949, he worked with Henry Kaplan in adapting the linear accelerator for the treatment of cancer. He directed Project M, which led to the construction of the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (a two-mile linear accelerator). In 1948, Ginzton helped found Varian Associates, becoming chairman of the board and chief executive officer in 1959. Ginzton was elected a member of the National Academy of Science and the National Academy of Engineering; he has also served on the Stanford University Board of Trustees.
Description of the Collection
Papers regarding Ginzton's activities at Stanford University, with Varian Associates, and on national committees and local organizations. Includes correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, journals, publications, technical reports, manufacturing reports, oral history materials, and photographs. Also includes correspondence, publications, biographical material and manuscripts of Russell, Sigurd and Dorothy Varian.
Microwaves.; Research and Development Contracts.; Microelectronics industry -- California -- Santa Clara County.; Science and industry.; Physics.; High Technology Industry -- California -- Santa Clara County.; Science -- History.; Klystrons.; Mid-Peninsula Housing Coalition.; Varian, Sigurd Fergus; Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard); Stanford Linear Accelerator Center; National Academy of Sciences.; Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard); Stanford University. Department of Physics. Faculty; Stanford Midpeninsular Urban Coalition.; Stanford University. W.W. Hansen Laboratory of Physics; Kaplan, Henry S.; Varian, Russell Harrison; Hansen, W. W. (William Webster); Stanford University. Microwave Laboratory; Varian, Dorothy
- Personal papers, Series 1
  - Ginzton- Biographies, Publications, Photographs, Stanford Ph. D. Thesis (1939); Notebook from Electronics Class conducted by Karl Spangenberg; Letters of Tribute on the Occasion of the 15th Anniversary of the Urban Coalition and of Retirement from Varian (Box 2)
  - Manuscripts (Box 2)
  - Teaching notes (physics) (Box 2)
  - Dedication of Biophysics Laboratory, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Ginzton PERSONAL Correspondence, 1960-1972 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with Ansel Adams, 1959-1980 (Box 3A)
  - Stanford correspondence, 1956-1961 (Box 3A)
  - Ginzton Telephone Conversations with Chodorow amp; Stearns (1947) (Box 3B)
  - Early Stanford Correspondence (1937-1945) (Box 3B)
  - Microwave Measurements Textbook - Correspondence (Box 3B)
  - Microwave Measurements Book - Revised Edition (Box 3B)
  - Ginzton PERSONAL Correspondence (1969, 1971, 1973-1980, 1981-1983) (Box 3B)
  - Ginzton/SLAC Correspondence (1959-1968) (Box 3B)
  - Stanford Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 7)
  - Early Klystron notes, 1937-1940 (Box 8)
  - Material pertaining to membership in SEAC (Scientific and Educational Advisory Committee) for LBL (1976-1978) (Box 17)
  - The "$100 Idea" - published article (Box 21)
  - Michael Wolff Correspondence concerning the "$100 Idea (Box 21)
  - Speeches (Box 2, Box 14B)
  - Teaching Material (Box 9)
  - Urban Coalition; Housing Development Corp (Box 7, Box 7A)
- Russell and Sigurd Varian families: Correspondence, biographical materials, photographs, Series 2
  - New Information on Varian Klystrons (1952) (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Report on the Investigation of Silicone Fluids (1945) (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Brief Description of a Precise Microwave Omni- Directional Radio Range (1947) (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Fixed Grid Invar Reflex Klystron Frequency Stability "S" Band (Box 10)
  - Engineering Bulletins R&D Plant - Estimates, Specifications, etc (1951-1953) (Box 10)
  - Electron Tube Conference - Stanford (1953) (Box 10)
  - Reprints; Misc. (Box 10)
  - Stanford Research Institute (1952) (Box 10)
  - Engineering Reports (Box 10)
  - Correspondence; Technical Reports (Box 10)
  - Klystron Grids - by Russell H. Varian (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Rhenium Plating for Klystron Grids (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Investigation of Cycleweld Process (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Theory of Modulation of Reflex Klystrons - Basic Small Signal Theory (Box 10)
  - Graphical Methods for Analysis of Velocity Modulation Bunching (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - State of Development of Metal Ceramic Tubes in Germany (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - Characteristics of the Type 410-R Klystron (Box 10)
  - Sperry Gyroscope - "C" Band Fixed Grid Invar Reflex Klystron Frequency Stability (Box 10)
  - Aircraft - Finishes, Standard Mech. Parts &Materials - S. Varian (Box 10)
  - R. Varian Speech - Brooklyn Poly. - 1944 Ph.D. Award, 0 (Box 19)
  - R. L. Wathen's Statement No. 1 - 1944, 0 (Box 19)
  - R. L. Wathen's Statement No. 2 - 1944, 0 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence with R. L. Wathen and Smithsonian Inst. (1958-1974), 0 (Box 19)
  - Photographs of the Varian brothers, etc., 0 (Box 19)
  - NMR - Instrument Div., 0 (Box 19)
  - Statement by W.W. Hansen and Memo from D. L Webster (1937), 0 (Box 19)
  - Notes from R. H. Varian Notebook (1937), 0 (Box 19)
  - Statement of S. F. Varian (1944), 0 (Box 19)
  - Webster - Dorothy Varian Interview (1961), 0 (Box 19)
  - The Klystron by E. L. Ginzton (1954), 0 (Box 19)
  - The Invention and Development of the Klystron by Russell H. Varian (1948), 0 (Box 19)
  - Writings of Russell and Sigurd Varian, 0 (Box 19)
  - Writings of W. W. Hansen, 0 (Box 19)
  - Varian Family - by Dorothy Varian, 0 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence - Varian Family - Early Period, 0 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence - Sigurd Varian (1927), 0 (Box 19)
  - Varian - 25th Anniversary Material, 0 (Box 19)
  - Russell Varian - Draft Article "Invention, 0 (Box 19)
  - Varian Associates - Miscellaneous (1948), 0 (Box 19)
  - S. F. Varian: Notes for a Book, 0 (Box 19)
  - Stanford-Varian Agreements and Related Material, 0 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence w/Sig and Winnie (1946-1949) and R. H. Varian: Invention of NMR, 0 (Box 19, Folder 0)
  - Stanford Correspondence (1937), 0 (Box 19)
  - On the Resonant Frequency of Closed Concentric Lines by W.W. Hansen, 0 (Box 19)
  - R. H. Varian - History of the Klystron - Collated Material, 0 (Box 19)
  - R. H. Varian - Sperry Royalties, 0 (Box 19)
- Varian Associates, Series 3
  - Ginzton/Varian Correspondence (1970-1971) (Box 3)
  - Varian Ad Hoc Management Committee (1968) (Box 3)
  - Varian Board of Directors' Miscellaneous Correspondence (1960-1985) (Box 4)
  - Varian Board of Directors' Board Vacancies (1962-1971) (Box 4)
  - Ad Hoc Committee of the Board (James Halt Report) (Box 4)
  - Directors' Nights (1965-1967) (Box 4)
  - Directors' European Trip (1967) (Box 4)
  - President's Planning Committee - Strategic Planning (1983) (Box 4)
  - Central Staff Meetings (1973-1981) (Box 4)
  - Vallco Park (1962-1964) (Box 4)
  - N. F. Parker (Employment of—) (Box 4)
  - N. F. Parker - Miscellaneous (1981) (Box 4)
  - E. J. Barlow - Miscellaneous (1981-1983) (Box 4)
  - E. L. Ginzton - Diaries (1957-1962) (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors' Board Dinner (1983) (Box 5)
  - Board Committee on Long Range Planning (1964) (Box 5)
  - Chairman's Advisory Committee Correspondence (1962-1965) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors' Meeting - Salt Lake City (1979) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors' Meeting - Massachusetts (1978) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors' Meeting - Boston (1976) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors* Meeting - Canada (1975) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors - Policy Committee Agenda & Minutes (1973-1980) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors - Policy Committee (1975-1980) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors - Policy Committee - Financial Objectives (1974-1975) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors - Policy Committee - Nonfinancial Objectives (1975) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors - Policy Committee - Objectives & Policies (1973-75) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors - Policy Committee - Miscellaneous (1973-1977) (Box 5)
  - Basic Objectives (1957) (Box 5)
  - Interoffice Memos - Central Research (1962-1964) (Box 5)
  - CFTH Meeting (1965) (Box 5)
  - CFTH-Varian Meetings (1965-1968) (Box 5)
  - CFTH - General (1959-1961) (Box 5)
  - CFTH - Minutes and Reports (1961) (Box 5)
  - B. I. Roundtable - Bermuda (1966) (Box 5)
  - B. I. Roundtable - French Lick (1962) (Box 5)
  - Atlas-Wercke (1963) (Box 5)
  - CLEAR Installation (1962) (Box 5)
  - Early Varian Associates Checkbook (Box 8)
  - Early Varian Associates Organization Correspondence (Box 8)
  - James Du Prau File (1962-1963) (Box 12)
  - CMC Minutes (1966-1968) (Box 12)
  - CMC Memoranda (1966-1967) (Box 12)
  - E. P. Courtlllot Reports (1959-1961) (Box 12)
  - Chairman's Advisory Committee (1959-1964) (Box 12)
  - Eimac Merger (1965) (Box 12)
  - E. L. Ginzton Shareholders' Meetings Speeches (1969-1983) (Box 14A)
  - E. L. Ginzton Chronological Files (1979-1985) (Box 15)
  - E. L. Ginzton Chronological Files (1974-1978) (Box 16)
  - E. L. Ginzton Expense Reports (1970-1972) and (1977-1985) (Box 16)
  - Varian material pertaining to CT Scanners (1976-1979) (Box 18)
  - Varian - 25th Anniversary Material (Box 19)
  - Varian Associates - Miscellaneous (1948) (Box 19)
  - Varian Foundation (Box 22)
- Technical material on early accelerators, Series 4
  - The Maxitron 1000 X-Ray Therapy Unit - G.E. Corp. (1950) (Box 11)
  - Integral Doses for 200 kv X-Rays and for Megavolt Radiation by R. WIderbe - Baden, Switzerland (undated) (Box 11)
  - Megavolt Radiation Cancer Therapy brochure presented to E. L. Ginzton from Allis-Chalmers Mfg. Co. (1947-1949) (Box 11)
  - Stanford MW Lab. Report 439 - "A Theoretical Analysis of Linear Accelerators using Equivalent Circuits and Cavity Normal Modes" by IJedrick (1958) (Box 11)
  - Development of an Electron Gun for Linear Accelerators by Karl Brown (1956) (Box 11)
  - Pearson Medical Accel. Power Supply (1952) (Box 11)
  - Report on Fabrication of the Linear Accelerator - Stanford MW Lai). - submitted by R. J. Lewandowski (1954) (Box 11)
  - High Voltage Engineering Corp. - Accelerators for High Voltage Therapy (1951) (Box 11)
  - RSI Reprint: Becker and Caswell - "Operation of a Six MeV Linear Electron Accelerator" (undated) (Box 11)
  - Sperry Gyroscope Co. Review, SRI, ARCO (undated) (Box 11)
  - X-Ray Material (various) (Box 11)
  - Electroforming Reprints (Box 11)
  - Biological Evaluation of 20 Million Volt Roentgen Rays IV. Efficiency and Dosage Range by Quastler and Lanzl (1950) (Box 11)
  - Physical Basis for the High Skin Tolerance of Supervoltage Roentgen Rays by Trump (1948) (Box 11)
  - Survey Methods for Fast and High-Energy Neutrons by Burton Moyer (1952) (Box 11)
  - J Papers on Radiography - American Soc. for Testing Materials Mtg. (1949) (Box 11)
  - The Theory of Amplification in Non-Linear-Reactance Modulators by Hines (Box 11)
  - Large Signal Bunching in Velocity Modulated Electron Beams by Mihran and Webber (undated) (Box 11)
  - An Economical Industrial X-Ray Detector by Frerichs and Jacobs (1951) (Box 11)
  - Current Research in Radiobiology by Alma Howard and Michael Ebert (1953) (Box 11)
  - Reprint from NUCLEONICS - The Resonant Transformer: ASource of High- Energy Electrons by Knowlton, Mahn, and Ranftl (1953) (Box 11)
  - Reprint from NUCLEONICS - Relative Merits of Cathode Rays and Gamma Radiations by Goldblith and Proctor (1954) (Box 11)
  - Reprint from NUCLEONICS - Application of Isotopic Sources to Food &Drug Sterilization by Cream, Isaacs, Weiss, and Fahnoe (1953) (Box 11)
- Stanford linear accelerators, Series 5
  During the period of 1945 to 1965 we built ten linear accelerators at Stanford for a variety of purposes. These were:
  Mark I.
  The first accelerator employing one 1 megawatt magnetron was built by Bill Hansen to verify his theoretical calculations for a traveling-wave accelerator. It worked almost immediately and provided the basis for a proposal to the Office of Naval Research to build a billion volt machine. Mark I., itself, operated at a variety of energies, up to 6 MeV, as Hansen extended its length to about six feet.
  Mark II.
  Between 1947 and 1948, proposals were made to the Office of Naval Research to build a Mark III. to be powered by 22 high power klystrons and to be 220 feet in length. To test the validity of the design, a single ten-foot accelerator section was built by Richard Post, a graduate student working with Hansen (and later by Schiff). In almost every detail the Mark II. was a prototype of the Mark III. - except that it was only ten feet in length. It was completed by 1949 and served some high energy physics research.
  Mark III.
  This was to be a billion volt accelerator which grew in length as tenfoot sections were added in steps and eventually provided nearly a billion volts.
  Mark IV.
  After several years of use, the Mark III. clearly showed that an accelerator of this kind could be extended to very high energies but that various components of the machine needed to be improved. A proposal was made in 1956 to build a two-section machine but with all of the components being redesigned to represent the ultimate in the state-of-the-art technology. Also, the machine was to be built in a vault underneath the street level and to supply its beam to a special room to be used for study of electron therapy of cancer by Dr. Kaplan and others. The machine was used for a number of years both as a test vehicle for the Project Maccelerator components and as a pioneering effort to use high energy electrons for cancer treatment directly.
  Mark V.
  A 2 MeV S-band accelerator built to test principles of the undulator. It was built by a number of people including Motz, Mallory, and others.
  Mark VI.
  An X-band accelerator - at 3 MeV employing a Stanford-built 1 megawatt, 3 centimeter klystron. This accelerator was to be used specifically for generation of millimeter waves from electrons by means of the Motz undulator.
  Mark VII.
  An accelerator guide and klystron, and certain components built in our laboratory and supplied to Argonne National Laboratory.
  Mark VIII.
  A waveguide supplied to General Electric Company for their tests as a part of a collaborative project between General Electric and Stanford.
  Mark IX.
  An accelerator developed at the Microwave Laboratory as a part of a project to supply Michael Reese Hospital with an electron accelerator for electron treatment of cancer. Dr. Ulman at Michael Reese used it for a number of years. The components, other than accelerator guides, were built largely for Michael Reese Hospital by Helene Certiss Industries
  Mark X.
  A 6 MeV linear accelerator designed specifically for Dr. Kaplan to be used in San Francisco for x-ray and electron therapy.
  - Mark I. Accelerator: Proposed Linear Accelerator Book - Chapters 1, 2, 3 and 4 (Box 3B)
  - Report on the Stanford Linear Electron Accelerator by W. W. Hansen, dated November 26, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Accelerating the Electron" - August 15, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Photographs of Mark I. (Box 6)
  - Mark II. Accelerator; Report by Richard F. Post, dated October 1950 (Box 6)
  - Mark III. (Box 6)
  - Minutes of the Staff Meetings describing the progress of construction of the Mark III. machine. (Box 6)
  - Reprint of an article from RSI for February 1955 describing the Stanford high energy linear accelerator (Mark III.) (Box 6)
  - Proposal for a 2-Mile Linear Electron Accelerator dated ApriI 1957 (Box 6)
  - Material from Congressional Hearings and Other Sources Describing the Proposed Project M (Box 6)
  - Various Reports and Material pertaining to the Congressional Authorization of Project Mand Record of its Construction and Completion (Box 6)
  - Medical Accelerator - A Paper by Ginzton and Kaplan entitled, Some Considerations of the Potential Usefulness and Design of Linear Accelerators for Medical Applications (Box 6)
  - The Proposed Stanford 2-Mile Linear Electron Accelerator. Sutement of E. L. Ginzton, Stanford University, July 14, 1959. Part of Congressional Testimony in support of Project M. (Box 6)
- Medical accelerators, Series 6
  - A Conversation with Henry S. Kaplan (December 7, 1983) (Box 13)
  - Proceedings - Ninth Varian Clinac Users Meeting (May 1982) (Box 13)
  - Kaplan Commemorative Issue of Red Journal - Some Notes (Box 13)
  - Radiation Therapy with High Energy Electrons - Microwave Laboratory Reports and Reprints (includes Clinical Experience) (Box 13)
  - Ginzton-Kaplan Correspondence in Connection with Medical Accelerator Work (Box 13)
  - Some Considerations of the Potential Usefulness and Design of Linear Electron Accelerator for Medical Applications" by Kaplan and Ginzton. First Proposal for the Medical Machine at Stanford. (Box 13)
  - Tentative Decisions concerning Design and Construction of the Medical Accelerator" (1952) (Box 13)
  - Technical Report - "Design of Linear Electron Accelerators" by N. C. Chang (July 1953) (Box 13)
  - Medical Electron Accelerator for X-Ray Production" - Requirements and Desirable Features as Stated by Dr. Kaplan (1951) (Box 13)
  - Letter from U.S.P.H.S. to Ginzton notifying us of the First Year's Funding of the Medical Accelerator (Box 13)
  - Final Report on the Design, Development and Testing of Medical Linear Electron Accelerator for High-Energy Radiation Therapy" - (September 1952-August 31, 1957) (Box 13)
  - The Stanford Medical Linear Accelerator" - in three parts - by Kaplan, Ginzton, and Others (Box 13)
  - Electron Linear Accelerators for Radiation Therapy: History, Principles, and Contemporary Developments" by Karzmark and Pering (1973) (Box 13)
  - Reprint of "The Supervoltage Story" by Miltord D. Schulz (August 1975) (Box 13)
- Trip reports, Series 7
  - England and France (1944-1945) (Box 23)
  - B. I. Trip to Moscow (1964) (Box 23)
  - Trip to Hungary (1966) (Box 23)
  - Trip to Moscow (1970) (Box 23)
  - Trip to South America (1971) (Box 23)
  - Trip to the USSR (1972) (Box 23)
  - Trip to Chicago (1970) (Box 24)
  - Trip to Russia (1974) (Box 24)
  - Trip to Washington, DC (1975) (Box 24)
  - Trip to Bulgaria (1972) (Box 24)
  - Trips to Russia (1977, 1978, 1979, 1.981, 1982) (Box 24)
  - Trip Report - Bagshaw & Nunan - to USSR (May/June 1975) (Box 25)
  - Trip to Japan (1978) (Box 25)
  - Trip to Europe (1979) (Box 25)
  - Trip to Washington, DC (1981) (Box 26)
  - Trip to Saudi Arabia (1981) (Box 26)
  - Trip to Washington, DC (1982) (Box 26)
  - Trip to China (1984) (Box 26)
  - Trip to Palm Springs, CA (Varian User's Meeting) (19S4) (Box 26)
  - Stanford Trip to China (1978) (Box 26)
  - Report of a Visit to the People's Republic of China by the Second Stanford International Security and Anns Control Group (December 8-14, 1979) (Box 26)
  - Cancer in China" - book by Henry Kaplan (Box 27)
  - Trips to China (1979, 1980, 1981, 1983) (Box 27)
- Patents, Series 8 (Box 1)
- Stanford technical reports, Series 9
  - Early English Reports on Linear Accelerators (1946-1947) (Box 20)
  - Upper & Lower Bounds of Eigen-Values for Composite-Type Regions by Chu (Box 20)
  - X-Ray Protection by William Hansen (Box 20)
  - Linear Elec. Accelerator Project - Microwave Lab. (1948) (Box 20)
  - Electroforming of Copper for High-Vacuum Applications by LaForge, Jr. (1955) (Box 20)
  - Electroforming of Linear Accelerator Structures by James Pope (1957) (Box 20)
  - Report on the Study of Electroforming of Copper in the Acid-Copper Bath by Eugene Loh (undated) (Box 20)
  - A Traveling-Wave Frequency Multiplier by David Bates (1957) (Box 20)
  - A Traveling-Wave Tube Using Coupled Coaxial Cavities by B. Arfin (1956) (Box 20)
  - Velocity Distribution of Electrons In Gap-Modulated Electron Beams" by Perry B. Wilson (1958) (Box 20)
  - G. E. Catalogues for Supplies and Accessories (X-Ray) (1953) (Box 20)
  - A Study of the Generation of Sub-Millimeter Radiation by High-Energy Electrons in Waveguide" by Robert Whitehurst (1958) (Box 20)
  - A General Theory of Klystrons with Arbitrary, Extended Interaction Fields" by Tore Wessel-Berg (1957) (Box 20)
  - Shunt Impedance of Klystron Cavities by E. J. Nalos (1955) (Box 20)
  - The Focusing of Sheet Beams by P. A. Sturrock (1957) (Box 20)
  - Large-Signal Klystron Theory by P. A. Sturrock (1957) (Box 20)
  - The Stanford Mark III Linear Accelerator by R. B. Neal (1956) (Box 20)
  - Design of Linear Electron Accelerators with Beam Loading" bv R. B. Neal (1957) (Box 20)
  - A High Energy Linear Electron Accelerator" by R. B. Neal (1953) (Box 20)
  - The Institution of Electrical Engineers International Convention on MW Valves - "An Experimental Investigation of Velocity-Modulated Electron Beams" by Cullen and Stephenson (1958) (Box 20)
  - IEEE - "An Instrument for the Absolute Measurement of Low-Level Microwave Power in the 3 cm Band" by Cullen and French (1957) (Box 20)
  - IEEE - "The Comparison and Calibration of Power-Measuring Equipment at Wavelengths of 3 cm and 10 cm" by Bailey, French and Lane (1954) (Box 20)
  - IEEE -"A Torque-Ope rated Wattmeter for 3-cm Microwaves" by Cullen and Stephenson (1952) (Box 20)
  - IEEE - "Propagation of the Circular HOI Low-Loss Wave Mode Around Bends in Tubular Metal Waveguide" by Barlow (1957) (Box 20)
  - IEEE - "The Use of Dielectric Materials to Enhance the Reflectivity of a Surface at Microwave Frequencies" by Walker and Hyman (1958) (Box 20)
  - IEEE - "Mode Separation at the *r Mode in a Dielectric Loaded Waveguide Cavity" by Walker and West (1957) (Box 20)
  - Proposal for Research on Dielectric Loaded Waveguides by E.L. Lewis (Box 20)
  - Dielectric for Tube Windows and Slow Wave Structures" by Walker (University of British Columbia) (I960) (Box 20)
  - Vacuum Breakdown at Dielectric Surfaces" by Hayes (University of British Columbia) (I960) (Box 20)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1991-113
  - Committee on Nuclear and Alternative Energy (CONAES) reports and books (Box 1)
  - DOE reports (Box 2)
  - CONAES Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 3)
  - ELG Expense Reports (CONAES), 1975-1979 (Box 3)
  - Synthesis Panel, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Demand/Conservation panel, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
  - Reports Review Committee Comments on CONAES Report, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
  - CONAES Panel Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 6)
  - CONAES--Miscellaneous, 1975-1979 (Box 7)
  - Latest Draft of CONAES Report (Box 8)
  - Memorandum to CONAES, Members and Panel Chairmen, from John O. Berga, Sept. 1978 (Box 8)
  - Two copies of Dr. Kohn's COAL draft. (Box 8)
  - Chapter 4 to 11, COAL (Box 8)
  - Memorandum to CONAES, Committee Members and Panel Chairmen from E.L. Ginzton. (Box 8)
  - The final Report of the CONAES, (Review draft), July, 1977 (Box 8)
  - CONAES, Final Report - Chapter n - IX (Box 8)